Guide to the Carling I. Malouf Papers 1891-2006
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Slides, 1939-1975; Series IV; 5.0 linear feet
  - Old World, some Montana, undated (Boxbox-folder 88/7)
  - Plains Indians, undated (Box-folder 88/8)
  - Peyote, undated (Box-folder 88/9)
  - Charlie Russell and Paul Kane, undated (Box-folder 88/10)
  - John Woodenlegs, Cheyenne, Honorary Doctorate, University of Montana, 1978 (Box-folder 88/11)
  - Family Reunion, 1990 (Box-folder 88/12)
  - Cahokia, undated (Box-folder 88/13)
  - Peter Lefthand Award, undated (Box-folder 88/14)
  - Upper Missouri, Great Lakes, Wisconsin, undated (Box-folder 88/15)
  - Forest Fires, Western Montana, circa 1980 (Box-folder 88/16)
  - Alaska Indian and Eskimo Arts and Crafts, undated (Box-folder 88/17)
  - Bahamas, undated (Box-folder 88/18)
  - Mormons, Nebraska to Utah, undated (Box-folder 88/19)
  - Texas Views, undated (Box-folder 88/20)
  - Montana Historic, Montana Prehistory, undated (Box-folder 88/21)
  - Skeletal / Burial, RESTRICTED, circa 1970 (Box-folder 89)
- Moving Image Material, circa 1950-1980; Series V; 2.5 linear feet
  This series consists of moving image material filmed by or collected by Carling Malouf. Most of the titles assigned are as given by Malouf (when the material was labeled.) In 2021, films were viewed and content descriptions provided when possible. Commercial films were removed from the series in 2021.
  A film of Malouf's class at Cromwell Island on Flathead Lake is restricted because it shows the location of a Native American burial site.
  - Anthropologists, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 75 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 1)
  - Arline, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 125 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 2)
  - Army Scenes, Army Prison Camp, ca. 1977; Super 8 mm; Color, 300 ft, No Sound (Reel 3)
  - Camas Field, Lolo Pass, undated; "Camas Field, Lolo Pass, Pocher Meadow"; Super 8 mm; Color, 50 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 4)
  - Children Playing, ca. 1961; 16 mm; Black and White, 100 ft, No Sound (Reel 5)
  - Cities, ca. 1960; Old Spanish Trail; 8 mm; Color, 300 ft, No Sound (Reel 6)
  - Custer Battlefield Scenes, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 75 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 7)
  - For Sydney, Benjamin, undated; Shots of baby and family; Super 8 mm; Color, 25 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 8)
  - Fort Owen, ca. 1970s; Super 8 mm; Color, 200 ft, Magnetic Sound; Digital Copy Available (Reel 9)
  - Friends, ca. 1967; 8 mm; Color, 150 ft, No Sound (Reel 10)
  - Historical Archaeology, undated; 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, No Sound (Reel 11)
  - Historical Archaeology, Fur Trade to Fort Missoula, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 12)
  - Kids, ca. 1960s; Shots of children playing, zoo, kids at amusement park, baby birthday party, family trip to Washington, D.C., various outdoor shots, and a graduation.; 8 mm; Color, 300 ft, No Sound (Reel 14)
  - Kids II, ca. 1960s; Shots of family meal, snow shoveling, graduation, and mowing the lawn at a house; 8 mm; Color, 100 ft, No Sound (Reel 15)
  - Mary Ann, T. Dick, and Mary, undated; Shots of people talking and children. Shots of windmill (possibly part of a family vacation); Super 8 mm; Color, 100 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 16)
  - Montana, ca. 1970s; Various landscape shots of Montana taken by boat, various mountain landscape shots, shots of orchestra and people outside, night shots, shots of people snow mobiling.; 8 mm; Color, 200 ft, No Sound (Reel 20)
  - Montana, Sentinel, Pattee Canyon Fires, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 75 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 21)
  - Montana Archaeology, Fort Owen, a. 1971; 8 mm; Color, 350 ft, No Sound; Digital Copy Available (Reel 22)
  - Montana Native Americans, ca. 1970; 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, No Sound; Digital Copy Available (Reel 23)
  - Native American, University of Montana, Native American Studies, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 300 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 24)
  - Nez Perce War Camp Equipment, undated; Fort Fizzle lecture and shots of surrounding landscape. Nez Perce War Cannal Scenes, Camp Equimpent; Super 8 mm; Color, 25 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 27)
  - Pipeline, Wyoming, 1956-1957; Pipeline-wyo-colo 1956-1957; Super 8 mm; Color, 20 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 29)
  - Relatives, ca. 1960s; Shots of friends and relatives on vacation. Shots of children playing. Shots of family outside in summer, shots of a funeral.; 8 mm; Color, 300 ft, No Sound (Reel 31)
  - Some Historic Montana Mines: Bannack, Bear Mouth, Garnet, Argenta, Sylvan TTC, undated; Super 8 mm; Color, 200 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 32)
  - Sydney and Dick, ca. 1960s-1970s; Shots of woman with a baby, various shots of baby including first steps. Shots of 2 babies together, shots of carnival. Shots of newborn including "Dick's 1st Birthday"; 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, No Sound (Reel 35)
  - Sydeny and Dick at Fort Missoula, ca. 1970s; Shots of a gathering of people at Fort Missoula; Super 8 mm; Color, 50 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 36)
  - Taylor, Cutler, ca. 1977-1980s; Shots of church, people with shovels near a bush, woman with baby, snowball fight, family at beach, Missoula. Shots of Illinois, family gathering, airshow, and various shots of family.; 8 mm; Color, 150 ft, No Sound (Reel 37)
  - Texas and Tita, ca. 1970s; Shots of landscape (from airplane?), lake, HINDs factory, oil field, downtown stree, children, and family.; Super 8 mm; Color, 200 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 38)
  - Tita and Ziya Kino's Party, ca. 1970s; Shots of exterior and interior of house, family and friends gathered in house (for party), people playing instruments.; Super 8 mm; Color, 200 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 39)
  - Uncle Forest, ca. 1970s; "A.Er + Winder Quarters" Shots of landscape, man in forest, man and woman talking.; Super 8 mm; Color, 25 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 40)
  - Western Scenes, undated; 1) San Fancisco cable cars; 2) Square rigger at dock, San Fancisco; 3)Fog- Hills- Turn trees; 4)Beach in Wind; 5)Carmel Bay Monterey; 6)Muir Woods; 7) Nevada; 8) Gosiul and Great Salt Lake Desert; 9) Great Salt Lake Crossing; 10) Fish Lake; 11)Jordan River Valley; 12) Wasatch; 13) Utah Lake; 14) Ogden; 15)Wasatch; 16)Tim Panogas Area; 17) Seasons; 18) Quivah; 19) Mountains East of Tetons; 20) Mout Lasser; 21) Banff; 22) Glacier National Park Fire; 23) Gold Creek; 24) Yaak River; 25) Boys at Swan Lake; 26) Hungry Horse; 27) Flathead and Glacier National Park; 28) Yellowstone; 29) Tetons; 30) Arkansas River; 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, No Sound (Reel 42)
  - Wyoming Archaeolgy, ca. 1980s; Shots of Wyoming Archaeological Site and Landscape; 8 mm; Color, 25 ft, No Sound (Reel 43)
  - University of Montana Kindergarten, Christmas, 1954-1955; "University Kindergarten 1954-1955 XMAS" Shots of kindergarten chirstmas party and show, shots of children playing outside on playground; 8 mm; Color, 150 ft, No Sound (Reel 44)
  - Missoula, 1976; Shots taken around Missoula. Parade; Super 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 45)
  - Native American Dances, ca. 1970s-1980s; Native American dances at festival/ parade in Missoula. "Dancing around the World"; Super 8 mm; Color, 400 ft, Magnetic Sound (Reel 47)
  - Burials - RESTRICTED, 1970; Film of Malouf's class on a field trip and their excavation of Native American burial site on Cromwell Island, Flathead Lake, Montana. Film is restricted because it shows the location of the burial site.; 8 mm; Color, 100 ft, No Sound (Reel 48)